<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>IPCC ROOT - Peter Elmer</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/peter-elmer.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2017-02-14T10:37:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>The Princeton IPCC ROOT project begins</title><link href="/IPCC_ROOT_Kickoff.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-14T10:37:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-14T10:37:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Peter Elmer</name></author><id>tag:None,2017-02-14:/IPCC_ROOT_Kickoff.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Princeton/Intel Parallel Computing Center (IPCC ROOT) held its &lt;a href="https://indico.cern.ch/event/612658/"&gt;kick-off meeting&lt;/a&gt; today. The main IPCC ROOT engineer, &lt;a href="https://github.com/vgvassilev/"&gt;Vassil Vassilev&lt;/a&gt; joined Princeton and the IPCC ROOT project in January, 2017. He presented the &lt;a href="https://ipcc-root.github.io/downloads/20170217-ipcc-princeton.pdf"&gt;initial IPCC ROOT workplan for 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ROOT is a data analysis framework which enables big data processing …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Princeton/Intel Parallel Computing Center (IPCC ROOT) held its &lt;a href="https://indico.cern.ch/event/612658/"&gt;kick-off meeting&lt;/a&gt; today. The main IPCC ROOT engineer, &lt;a href="https://github.com/vgvassilev/"&gt;Vassil Vassilev&lt;/a&gt; joined Princeton and the IPCC ROOT project in January, 2017. He presented the &lt;a href="https://ipcc-root.github.io/downloads/20170217-ipcc-princeton.pdf"&gt;initial IPCC ROOT workplan for 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ROOT is a data analysis framework which enables big data processing, statistical analysis, visualization and storage in highly efficient manner. ROOT is open source software. The focus of the IPCC ROOT project is the modernization of the ROOT Math and I/O libraries.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="news"></category></entry><entry><title>Announcing the Princeton IPCC ROOT project</title><link href="/Announcing_IPCC_ROOT.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-03T10:37:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-05-03T10:37:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Peter Elmer</name></author><id>tag:None,2016-05-03:/Announcing_IPCC_ROOT.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Intel has funded an &lt;a href="https://software.intel.com/en-us/articles/intel-parallel-computing-center-at-princeton-university-high-energy-experiment"&gt;Intel Parallel Computing Center (IPCC) at Princeton University&lt;/a&gt; who main target is the modernization of critical libraries in the &lt;a href="https://root.cern.ch/"&gt;ROOT&lt;/a&gt; data analysis framework. ROOT is a data analysis framework which enables big data processing, statistical analysis, visualization and storage in highly efficient manner. ROOT is open …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Intel has funded an &lt;a href="https://software.intel.com/en-us/articles/intel-parallel-computing-center-at-princeton-university-high-energy-experiment"&gt;Intel Parallel Computing Center (IPCC) at Princeton University&lt;/a&gt; who main target is the modernization of critical libraries in the &lt;a href="https://root.cern.ch/"&gt;ROOT&lt;/a&gt; data analysis framework. ROOT is a data analysis framework which enables big data processing, statistical analysis, visualization and storage in highly efficient manner. ROOT is open source software. It was begun nearly 20 years ago as part of the preparation for the scientific program of the &lt;a href="http://home.web.cern.ch/topics/large-hadron-collider"&gt;Large Hadron Collider&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href="http://home.web.cern.ch/"&gt;European Laboratory for Particle Physics (CERN)&lt;/a&gt;, but has been widely adopted in particle and nuclear physics. It is used not only at CERN and by external scientists working at CERN, but also for experiments at many other physics laboratories around the world. It is used daily by an estimated community of 20000 scientists around the world, including non-physics applications ranging from finance to genomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compute needs of the LHC program are very large and will grow in a way that there is a significant pressure to optimize software codes like ROOT. The focus of the IPCC ROOT project is the modernization of the ROOT Math and I/O libraries.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="news"></category></entry></feed>